netbase.com 2016-04-13

# Privacy Policy - NetBase

**Effective Date: March 26, 2013**

NetBase Solutions Inc. (“NetBase”, “we,” or “our”) provides insight discovery services (“Services”) to businesses (“Customers”). To provide the Services, NetBase hosts applications on designated websites, which extract deep meaning from text digital data.

NetBase social intelligence gives your marketing team a smarter way to monitor, understand, react, engage, and publish at the speed of social – through both owned and earned channels. NetBase is trusted by the largest brands and the most forward-thinking agencies, including Coca-Cola, ESPN, GfK, J.D. Power & Associates, Kenneth Cole, Kraft, and the Obama Campaign. NetBase powers the weekly Sentiment Tracker in the Wall Street Journal, and our solutions are sold globally by SAP AG. For more information, visit www.netbase.com, @NetBase, on Facebook page, LinkedIn, or YouTube.

NetBase recognizes that privacy is important, and that individuals have the right to know and understand what is being done with personal information that pertains to them, the choices available to them, and the steps that they can take to access this personal information and to request that inaccurate information be deleted.

In this document, “personal information” means information that pertains to an identified or identifiable individual. For example, personal information may include first and last name, user name, physical or electronic mail address, telephone number, or photograph. It may include statements or opinions of an individual person, such as a request for information or a search query, if it can be associated to that individual.

  1.  **Application: Only for Information Collected Through This Site**
  2.  **Consent and Choice**
  3.  **The Information that We Collect About You**
  4.  **How We Use Personal Information**
  5.  **Sharing Your Personal Information**
  6.  **Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies**
  7.  **Retention**
  8.  **User Generated Content**
  9.  **Security**
  10.  **Inquiries and Complaints**
  11.  **Amendments**
  12.  **Other Websites**
  13.  **How to Contact Us**

  1. ## APPLICATION: ONLY FOR INFORMATION COLLECTED THROUGH THIS SITE

This Privacy Statement applies only to the personal information that we may collect through Netbase.com (the “Site”) and to the activities and services in which Netbase engages through the Site. It does not apply to personal information that is contained in material to which Netbase has access in connection with its Services, or to Netbase’s offline activities.

  2. ## CONSENT AND CHOICE

    * ### Consent

By using Netbase.com, or providing personal information through the Site, you agree and consent to our collection, use, and disclosure of all personal information that we collect from you as a result of your use of the Sites in accordance with the terms below.

    * ### Choice/Changes to the Privacy Policy

If we change our personal information collection or use practices in a material way, we will endeavor to provide registered users with advance notice of the proposed changes by conspicuously posting notice of such changes on our Site.

  3. ## THE INFORMATION THAT WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU

We may collect information about you, including personal information, from a variety of sources, including, information that you voluntarily provide to us through our Site, information that we obtain from third party partners and marketing companies, and information that we collect about you automatically (see our section below entitled “Cookies and Other Tracking Devices”).

    * ### Information We Collect Directly From You

You may browse Netbase.com without directly providing any personal information to us. If you would like to request information from us or respond to a blog post, we will require you to submit information to us, including, your name, company name, address, and phone number (optional).

    * ### Forms

We collect personal information through forms that are posted on our Site, for example, in areas where we offer users access to newsletters, white papers and other material that NetBase has developed for distribution to third parties. This information may include name, address, telephone number, company name, or e-mail address, or the nature of a query made. In all such cases, you choose whether to provide us with the personally identifiable information.

    * ### Information that We Collect Automatically

We use cookies, web beacons, and other automated devices to collect information about visitors to our Site. Specifically, we may collect the following information about your use of our Site via these technologies: your browser type and operating system; your IP address; user language; the presence/absence of “flash” plug-ins, screen resolution, or connection type. We may collect this information with other personal information that we collect about you.

    * ### Children

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13 years old. If we determine that any personal information that we hold pertains to a child under 13, we immediately delete or block such information or any document containing such information.

  4. ## HOW WE USE PERSONAL INFORMATION

We use the personal information that we collect from users on the Site to respond to inquiries made by them, such as requests for information, request for a brochure or a white paper, request for a meeting, or to contact them when they have provided contact information.

We also use the personal information collected through the Site in aggregated form for statistical and web analytics purposes, in order to better understand how our users use the Site, the geographic area where they reside, generally to improve the Site usage and performance, as well as to identify enhancements to our products and Services.

We also will use your information for marketing and advertising purposes. For example, we may send you email communications about products and services that we believe may be of interest to you.

We also may use your personal information to protect our rights and interests, as well as other users of our Site, and where permitted or required by law.

  5. ## WITH WHOM WE SHARE PERSONAL INFORMATION

    * ### Service Providers

Like most organizations, we use service providers, which act on our behalf, or provide us with technical and other capabilities to operate our business. For example: communications or hosting. We require these organizations to agree in writing to use any personal information to which they have access solely to provide their services to Netbase, to protect any personal or confidential information to which they may have access in the course of their services, and to comply with all applicable legal requirements.

    * ### Legal process

We may disclose personal information to third parties (a) if we are required to do so by law; (b) if we believe that it is necessary in order to conform to the law, cooperate with law enforcement agencies, or comply with legal process served on us; (c) in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity; (d) if we believe, upon reasonable grounds, that it is necessary to protect the rights or property of Netbase or its customers; (e) if we believe it is necessary to pursue available remedies or limit any damages that Netbase may sustain, or to collect monies owed to Netbase.

    * ### Corporate transactions

We may transfer your personal information to another organization in the event of a merger or change of ownership of all or part of Netbase.

    * ### Third party marketing

We do not provide personally identifiable information to any third parties for their own marketing purposes.

  6. ## COOKIES AND OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES

We use cookies and web beacons (e.g., pixel tags) in order to gather information about how each user uses the Site, such as the time spent on a page, the frequency of the visits, or the click through. As stated above, we may collect your IP address, browser type, and domain name. Pixel tags cannot be removed because they reside in the code of the Site, rather than on the user’s computer. Additional information is below:

 **Cookies**.Cookies allow a web server to transfer data to a computer for recordkeeping and other purposes. We and our third party service providers may use “cookies” on our Site and Services to, among other things, better serve you with tailored information and facilitate your ongoing access to and use of the Sites and Services. For example, we may use cookies for efficient management of the servers providing our Sites including when you access the Services. In addition, we may use cookies to determine whether you are accessing the Sites or features of the Services from our Services or another Internet service provider. ****

There are two types of cookies: session-based and persistent cookies. In addition, we also allow third parties to use cookies on our Sites, such as for analytical purposes.

    *  **Session Cookies.** Session cookies exist only during an online session. They disappear from your computer when you close your browser or turn off your computer. We use session cookies to allow our systems to uniquely identify you during a session or while you are logged in to the Sites. This allows us to process your online transactions and requests and verify your identity, after you have logged in, as you move through our Sites.
    *  **Persistent Cookies.** Persistent cookies remain on your computer after you have closed your browser or turned off your computer. We use persistent cookies to track aggregate and statistical information about user activity, which may be combined with other user information.
    *  **Third Party Cookies.** We may also engage third parties to track and analyze non-personally and personally identifiable website data. To do so, we may permit third parties to apply cookies to users of our Site, where permitted by law. We use the data collected by such third parties to help us administer and improve the quality of the Site and to analyze site usage. Such third parties may combine the information that we provide about you with other information that they have collected. These third parties are required to use your information in accordance with this Policy.

 _Disabling Cookies_. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can edit your browser options to block them in future. The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your computer from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Visitors to our Site who disable their web browsers’ ability to accept cookies will be able to browse the Site.

 **Web Beacons, Pixel Tags and Other Technologies**. We use web beacons, such as clear GIFs, web bugs or pixel tags, which are tiny graphics with a unique identifier similar in function to cookies. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on your computer’s hard drive, clear GIFs are embedded invisibly on web pages. We may use clear GIFs in connection with our Site to, among other things, track the activities of Site visitors, help us manage content, and compile statistics about website usage. We and our third party service providers also use clear GIFs in HTML e-mails to our customers, to help us track the success of our marketing campaigns. Like many websites, the Site’s servers generate log files. These logs record aggregate information about site usage such as Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser types, Internet service providers, referring/exit pages, pages accessed, platform types, date/time stamps, times of use, and page views, for example. This information is necessary to analyze trends, administer the Site, balance web traffic, evaluate users’ electronic browsing in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.

 **Site Analytics**. Netbase works with third party service providers who use the technologies described in this section to conduct website analytics to help us track and understand how visitors use our Sites. For example, we use a variety of third party web analytics, to help us improve our Sites’ performance and user experiences.

  7. ## RETENTION

We keep the personal information that we collect only as long as it is required for the purpose for which it was collected. In addition, applicable laws or regulations, or specific requests from government authorities may require us to preserve and retain information for a longer period.

  8. ## USER GENERATED CONTENT

You may submit your own comments on certain portions of our Site, such as responding to a blog entry. Any information that you submit on our blog at Netbase.com will be viewable by all other visitors to this Site. Netbase is not responsible for the privacy of any information that you choose to submit through its Site, Services, or any public forum, such as a blog, or for the accuracy of any information contained in those postings. Any information that you disclose becomes public information. We cannot prevent such information from being used in a manner that may violate this Policy, the law, or your personal privacy.

  9. ## SECURITY AND CONFIDENTIALITY

We take reasonable steps to maintain physical, procedural, and technical security in our premises, information systems, and information storage facilities in order to protect personal information in our custody from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, erroneous disclosure, alteration, or destruction. Please be aware that no security is 100% secure.

  10. ## INQUIRIES AND COMPLAINTS

    * ### Inquiries

If you have any questions, comments, or complaints about this Privacy Statement, the collection, use, management, or disclosure of personal information from the Site, please contact us as set forth in the section “How to Contact Us” below.

    * ### Complaints and Dispute Resolution

If you wish to file a complaint or take issue with this Policy, or our handling of personal information that we collected from or through this Site, please direct such communication as indicated in the section “How to Contact Us” below. We will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes regarding our use and disclosure of Personal Information in accordance with the principles contained in this Policy.

  11. ## AMENDMENTS

We may change this Privacy Statement from time to time. We will post a prominent notice to this effect on the Site. We encourage you to frequently review this Privacy Statement for any modifications.

  12. ## OTHER WEBSITES

This Site may contain links to other websites or services that are owned and operated by third parties. We are not responsible for the policies or practices of websites to which the Site links. If you provide any information to such third parties, different rules regarding the collection and use of your personal information may apply. We strongly suggest you review such third party’s privacy policies before providing any personal information to them. You should contact these entities directly if you have any questions about their use of the information that they collect.

  13. ## HOW TO CONTACT US

If you have questions, comments, complaints about this Privacy Statement or our privacy, security or information protection practices, please send them by mail or by email as follows:  
Communications by mail:  
Privacy Office  
Netbase solutions, Inc.  
2087 Landings Drive  
Mountain View, CA  
Communications by email:  
privacy @ netbase.com
